Guide to the John L. De Forest Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
John L. De Forest papers
1875-2000
1934-2000
GEN MSS 885
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
11.83
(21 boxes) + 1 roll
The John L. De Forest Papers contain forty volumes of typescript diaries, 1935-2000, many with newspaper clippings and other related materials laid in. Diaries include entries relating to jazz musician and family friend Benny Goodman; Yiddish author Sholem Asch, for whom De Forest worked as a secretary in the 1940s; political associate John Davis Lodge, governor of Connecticut, 1951-1955; and Dutch historian and journalist Hendrik Willem Van Loon. The collection also includes typescript autobiographical writings and transcriptions of correspondence, based on excerpts from the diaries; research material and a biography of Tapping Reeve (1744-1823), Connecticut lawyer and educator, typescript draft; photographs of authors, musicians, and politicians represented in the diaries; photograph albums relating to family, friends, and the Brunswick School, Greenwich, Connecticut, 1930s-1940s; a scrapbook containing memorabilia from Oberlin College, 1935-1936; a scrapbook of clippings of newspaper articles written by De Forest for the Stamford Advocate and New Canaan Advertiser, about local news and Connecticut history, 1939-1940; scrapbooks of newspaper clippings concerning De Forest's work in Stamford politics, 1950s-1970s; scrapbooks of photographs, postcards, and ephemera relating to travel by De Forest in Europe, Canada, South America, and Mexico, 1940s-1950s; other newspaper clippings about local and national politics, 1920s-1970s; research materials on Connecticut history and De Forest family genealogy; and newsletters edited by De Forest for Electrolux.
De Forest, John L. (John Le Roy), 1916-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift and bequest of John L. De Forest, 1996-2000.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
John L. De Forest / Sholem Asch collection (GEN MSS 114)
John L. De Forest (1916-2000)
John L. De Forest, diarist and politician in Stamford, Connecticut. De Forest graduated from the Brunswick School, Greenwich, Connecticut, in 1935, and attended Oberlin College, 1935-1936. In the 1940s, De Forest worked as a secretary for Yiddish author Sholem Asch. For most of his life, De Forest lived in Stamford, where he was a member of the Republican Party, founded a Quaker Meeting in 1948, and served on the city Board of Representatives and Police Commission during the 1950s. During the 1970s, he worked in the factory personnel department of Electrolux, a home appliance manufacturer in Old Greenwich, Connecticut. De Forest kept a diary, 1935-2000, in which he recorded events of his daily life, observations on local and world events, and meetings with friends in politics and the arts.
Scope and Contents
The John L. De Forest Papers contain forty volumes of typescript diaries, 1935-2000, many with newspaper clippings and other related materials laid in. Diaries include entries relating to jazz musician and family friend Benny Goodman; Yiddish author Sholem Asch, for whom De Forest worked as a secretary in the 1940s; political associate John Davis Lodge, governor of Connecticut, 1951-1955; and Dutch historian and journalist Hendrik Willem Van Loon. The collection also includes typescript autobiographical writings and transcriptions of correspondence, based on excerpts from the diaries; research material and a biography of Tapping Reeve (1744-1823), Connecticut lawyer and educator, typescript draft; photographs of authors, musicians, and politicians represented in the diaries; photograph albums relating to family, friends, and the Brunswick School, Greenwich, Connecticut, 1930s-1940s; a scrapbook containing memorabilia from Oberlin College, 1935-1936; a scrapbook of clippings of newspaper articles written by De Forest for the Stamford Advocate and New Canaan Advertiser, about local news and Connecticut history, 1939-1940; scrapbooks of newspaper clippings concerning De Forest's work in Stamford politics, 1950s-1970s; scrapbooks of photographs, postcards, and ephemera relating to travel by De Forest in Europe, Canada, South America, and Mexico, 1940s-1950s; other newspaper clippings about local and national politics, 1920s-1970s; research materials on Connecticut history and De Forest family genealogy; and newsletters edited by De Forest for Electrolux.
Arrangement
Organized into two groupings: July 2000 Acquisition and September 1996 Acquisition.
Politicians -- Connecticut -- Stamford -- Archives; Quakers -- Connecticut -- Stamford; Society of Friends -- Connecticut -- Stamford; Stamford (Conn.: Town) -- Politics and government -- 20th Century; Stamford (Conn.: Town) -- Social life and customs; Diaries -- Connecticut -- Stamford -- 20th Century; Ephemera (general object genre) -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographs -- United States -- 20th Century; Scrapbooks -- United States -- 20th Century; Politicians -- Connecticut -- Stamford -- 20th Century; Asch, Sholem, 1880-1957; De Forest, John L. (John Le Roy), 1916-; De Forest family; Goodman, Benny, 1909-1986; Lodge, John Davis, 1903-1985; Reeve, Tapping, 1744-1823; Van Loon, Hendrik Willem, 1882-1944; Brunswick School (Greenwich, Conn.); Electrolux Group; Oberlin College; Republican Party (Conn.)
- July 2000 Acquisition, 1875-2000; 11; (19 boxes) + 1 roll
  Arrangement
  Organized into two subseries: Writings and Other Papers.
  - Writings
    - Diaries, volumes 1-7, 1935-1953; 7 (Box 1)
    - Diaries, volumes 8-15, 1953-1963; 8 (Box 2)
    - Diaries, volumes 16-22, 1963-1970; 7 (Box 3)
    - Diaries, volumes 23-30, 1970-1979; 8 (Box 4)
    - Diaries, volumes 31-37, 1979-1994; 7 (Box 5)
    - Diaries, volumes 38-40, 1995-2000; 4 (Box 6)
    - Diary excerpts, 1935-1961 (Box 6)
    - Diary excerpts, 1942-1959 (Box 6)
    - "School Days," typescript, [1994] (Box 6)
    - "A Barrister Builds A Schoolhouse," typescript, undated (Box 6)
    - "Student Days At Oberlin," typescript, 1935-1936; 3 (Box 6)
    - "Our Neighbor Benny Goodman," typescript, 1949-1986; 6 (Box 6)
    - "School Days, School Days. A Nostalgic Glance at an Academic Past," typescript, undated; 10 (Box 6)
    - "John Davis Lodge," typescript, 1950-1986; 3 (Box 6)
    - "Albert Bigelow," typescript, 1956-1997 (Box 7)
    - "Hendrik Willen Van Loon," typescript, 1939-1995 (Box 7)
    - "Once On A Long, Long Ridge," typescript, 1980-1985; 12 (Box 7)
    - "Small Ring--Big Fight, The Lachlan Slope, Love Letter," typescript, undated (Box 7)
    - "Stamford-Greenwich Meeting," diary excerpt, 1940-1990 (Box 7)
    - "Letters to Jack De Forest," typed transcripts, 1954-1984 (Box 7)
    - "Tributes to Mother," typed transcripts, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Other Papers
    - Recollections of Shadrach Brush, 1900 (Box 7)
    - Marshall Family genealogy, undated (Box 7)
    - Sholem Asch Christmas pageant, undated (Box 7)
    - Maps and town plans, 1875-1995, undated (Box 7)
    - Memberships and awards, 1951-1991 (Box 7)
    - Sons of the American Revolution, 1930-1990 (Box 7)
    - Electrolux Factory News, 1974-1976 (Box 7)
    - Newspapers, 1929-1969; 17 (Box 8)
    - Yale University Library Gazette, 1994-1999; 8 (Box 9)
    - De Forest, John L. Anthony De Forest of Stamford, Connecticut, 1739 (2 copies), 1983; 2 (Box 9)
    - The Original Proprietors, Descendants Of The Founders of Hartford (2 copies), 1986 (Box 9)
    - The First Ten Years: Yale Library Associates Endowment Fund, 1996 (Box 9)
    - The Beinecke Rare Book & Manuscript Library: A Guide To The Collections, 1994-1996 (Box 9)
    - Florence travel guide, 1970 (Box 9)
    - Maïeu, Bernard and André Pierrard. Promenade dans la mémoire de l'Avesnois. Tome 1: le cadre de vie, 1984 (Box 9)
    - Kreisel, Henrich. Würzburg: die alte Stadt, 1951 (Box 9)
    - Herbert Hoover presidential inauguration program, 1929 (Box 9)
    - Clippings, 1939-1996 (Box 9)
    - Genealogy research files, 1937-1975; undated; 5 (Box 9)
    - Photographs, 1964-1970; undated; 3 (Box 9)
    - Newspaper articles about De Forest, 1985-1999 (Box 9)
    - Scrapbook of newpapers articles by De Forest, 1939-1940 (Box 9)
      Scope and Contents
      Contains clippings from the Stamford Advocate and New Canaan Advertiser about local news and Connecticut history
    - Scrapbook about Brunswick School (Greenwich, Connecticut), circa 1934-1935 (Box 9)
    - Scrapbook about trip to Canada, 1940s (Box 9)
    - Scrapbook of humorous clippings, circa 1890 (Box 9)
    - Scrapbook of newspapers articles and printed material about De Forest and Connecticut politics, 1955-1960 (Box 10 (Oversize))
    - Scrapbook of newspapers articles and printed material about De Forest and Connecticut politics, 1960-1962 (Box 10 (Oversize))
    - Scrapbook of newspapers articles and printed material about De Forest and Connecticut politics, 1962-1963 (Box 11 (Oversize))
    - Scrapbook of newspapers articles and printed material about De Forest and Connecticut politics, 1963-1964 (Box 11 (Oversize))
    - Scrapbook of newspapers articles about De Forest and Connecticut politics, 1964-1968 (Box 12 (Oversize))
    - Clippings, printed material, and photographs about De Forest and Connecticut politics, 1960s-1970s; 2 (Box 13 (Oversize))
    - Clippings, printed material, and photographs about De Forest and Connecticut politics, 1960s-1970s; 2 (Box 14 (Oversize))
    - Scrapbook about trip to Europe, 1950s (Box 15 (Oversize))
    - Scrapbook about trip to Europe, 1950s (Box 16 (Oversize))
    - Scrapbook about trip to Mexico, 1940s (Box 17 (Oversize))
    - Scrapbook about trip to South America, 1940s (Box 17 (Oversize))
    - Scrapbook about Oberlin College, 1930s (Box 18 (Oversize))
    - Scrapbook of family and school photographs, 1930s-1940s (Box 18 (Oversize))
    - Sons of the American Revolution, 1935-1966 (Box 19 (Oversize))
    - Printed material, 1951 (Box 19 (Oversize))
    - Photograph of a school class, undated (Box 20 (Roll))
      Possibly Oberlin College
- September 1996 Acquisition, 1956, undated; 0.83; (2 boxes)
  Organized into two subseries: Research Materials about Tapping Reeve and Writings about Tapping Reeve.
  Contains materials relating to a biography of Tapping Reeve by De Forest
  - Research Materials about Tapping Reeve
    - "I. Reeve Family", undated (Box 21)
    - "II. Tapping Reeve (cont.)", undated (Box 21)
    - "III. Letters sent to Reeve", undated (Box 21)
    - "IV. Letters written by Reeve and Mrs. Reeve", undated (Box 21)
    - "V. Reeve material in Monitor", undated (Box 21)
    - "VI. The Witness. Articles", undated (Box 21)
    - "VII. Reeve notes from Fairfield Historical Society", undated (Box 21)
    - "VIII. Politics", undated (Box 21)
    - "IX. Law School Bldgs. and student letters", undated (Box 21)
    - "X. Aaron Burr and Edwards-Burr Family", undated (Box 21)
    - "XI. Law School Courses", undated (Box 21)
    - "XII. Reeve opinions and writings", undated (Box 21)
    - "XIII. History of Litchfield", undated (Box 21)
    - "XIV. Miscellany: Litchfield Republican, American Eagle, Enquirer", undated (Box 22)
    - "XV. Other letters by outsiders in which Reeves are mentioned", undated (Box 22)
    - "XVI. Religion in Litchfield", undated (Box 22)
    - "XVII. Notes on Jefferson with special references to policies that bothered Reeve and other Federalists", undated (Box 22)
    - "XVIII. William and Mary Law School", undated (Box 22)
    - "XIX. Bibliography", undated (Box 22)
    - "Statement to the Public by President Jacobs and Others on the Occasion of the Anniversary of Judge Tapping Reeve's Birth," Connecticut Bar Journal (Volume XXX, Number 3), 1956 September (Box 22)
  - Writings about Tapping Reeve
    - "Tapping Reeve -- Lawyer Extraordinary," The Connecticut Antiquarian (Volume VIII, Number 2), 1956 December (Box 22)
    - Tapping Reeve (biography), typescript, undated; 7 (Box 22)